# JOSPHAT KIPROP KIPLOMAN

# **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

GitHub | LinkedIn | Medium | Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

Full-Stack web developer with a background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 1+ year of experience, including mentoring 4+ junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. Strong skills include React, Database management, PostgreSQL, and Ruby

#### SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Redux, Tailwind, Bootstrap

Back-end: Ruby, NodeJs, Rails, Laravel, and ExpressJs

Test-Runners: Jest

Deployment: GitHub, Netlify, Heroku, Render, Vercel

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Version Control: Git and GitHub

Soft Skills: Problem-solving, Remote pair programming, and Teamwork

API: Restful Apis

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Rich-Digit Company

Naivasha, Kenya April 2023 - May 2023

Information Technology

- Communicated effectively with clients and non-technical stakeholders.
- Assisted in code reviews and fixing bugs to establish a uniform coding style.
- Implemented and optimized performance.
- I mastered using JWT in Rails.
- Boosted customer awareness from 40% to 75% through advertisement.

## Microverse Mentor (Volunteer)

Remote

May 2022 - Present

- Provided technical support through problem-solving procedures to junior web developers.
- Helped more than 100 students who were stuck in different areas.
- Developed over 20 projects reviewed and approved.

#### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

#### **Full Stack Web Developer**

April 2022 - Present

**E-COMMERCE-WEBSITE** — Ecomm website that shows all the products, can be filtered by names, and checkout using Mpesa and Paypal.

• Built with: HTML, CSS, React/Redux, Node/Express, Tailwind, and MongoDB.

link

**MY PORTFOLIO** - This is a portfolio that I developed using React, and Tailwind, it contains more details about me, my contacts, my projects, my skills, my resume download, and my cv download.

• Built with: HTML, React, React-Icons, and Tailwind.

### <u>Link</u>

**TUTOR'S APPOINTMENT APP** - This is a web application designed to facilitate the scheduling and management of tutoring sessions between tutors and students. It serves as a platform for tutors and students to connect, coordinate, and keep track of their tutoring appointments.

• Built with: React, Redux, Tailwind, Rails, and Postgresql.

# **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE March 2022 - Present

# Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Developed expertise in algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development.
- Completed the rigorous full-stack remote program where I created multiple projects using React, Ruby, HTML, CSS, and Vanilla Javascript. I also pair programmed remotely with other developers from all over the world.
- Obtained Full stack developer certificate.